Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford Collection 0006.023.001
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford
1866-2012
0006.023.001
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
30.0 Cubic feet Approximately 30 cubic feet 45 Boxes of Documents, 4 Oversized Boxes of Documents 2 Boxes of Videotapes, 1 Box Audiotapes 15 boxes of photographs, oversized photos
The earliest root of the modern Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford is found in the local Hebrew Benevolent Association or Society. The Association described itself a directories as having been "reorganized" in 1866. The Society dispensed aid during the two decades surrounding the turn of the century to the new immigrants arriving from Eastern Europe.
In 1901 the Jewish community began discussions for creating a new central, federated agency that would dispense charitable funds, but this agency would not come into being for another decade. In 1912, the United Jewish Charities formally organized under the slogan "the greatest good for the largest number with the least waste," and the Hebrew Benevolent Association was incorporated into this new organization.
Although the purpose of the UJC was to unify fundraising for local organizations, the UJC spun off several groups during the next several decades to achieve its aims. In the 1930s, it created the Hartford Jewish Council to coordinate existing fundraising campaigns among various institutions. In 1938, the UJC created the Hartford Jewish Welfare Fund to create a unified fundraising campaign for local, national, and overseas causes. In 1940, the UJC created the Jewish Community Council to address problems facing the local community. In 1940, the UJC changed its name to United Jewish Social Service Agency, reflecting this focus on providing social services. The United Jewish Social Service Agency eventually evolved into Jewish Family Service.
One early superintendent of the UJC in Hartford was Rebecca Affachiner (1920 1927) who later became known as the "Betsy Ross of Israel" when she flew her homemade Israeli flag in 1948.
During the World War II, the Jewish Community Council was active through its Army-Navy Committee, but in 1944 it transferred its assets to the USO-JWB (United Service Organization Jewish War Board) Army-Navy Committee.
In 1945, the Jewish Community Council and the Hartford Jewish Welfare Fund merged to form the Hartford Jewish Federation. During the next few decades, Hartford developed a national reputation for its philanthropy based upon the high per capita donation average. This average was high partially due to a substantial number of large gifts from prominent local businessmen.
Later, recessions combined with the opening up of non-Jewish organization to Jews took a toll on Hartford's exceptional donation record. Nevertheless, the Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford continues to support many important beneficiary agencies and contributes significantly to the fostering of Jewish charitable values.
Arrangement note
Provenance:
The Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford donated most of the material in this collection over the course of many years.
Arrangement:
The "General" files within the JFGH Document collection are arranged chronologically and contain a wide variety of items collected during the campaign. These files were originally collected in the Federation offices by a number of individuals employed at different times. Therefore, the materials these files do not necessarily contain information that document every single year.
The Federation photograph collection consists of both professional shots, most of which are black and white, and many snapshots. Although the majority of photos commemorate fund-raising events and other formal occasions, many document actual projects carried out by the Federation and its beneficiary organizations.
The photographs in this collection have been sorted into categories that correspond to those created for the papers files, such as Administration, Annual Campaign, etc. Further subseries have been developed for the photographs where appropriate.
Israel; Jewish Community; Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford; Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford; Jewish Organizations; Soviet Jewry
- Series I: Annual Campaign: General
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1988-1989 (2folders) (Box 1)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
- Series II: Annual Campaign: General
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
- Series III: Annual Campaign: General
  - Annual Campaign/General, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/General, 2007 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/General, n.d., undated (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/Century Club, 1980s (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/Builders and Allied Trades, 1990s (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/Farmington Valley Cabinet, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/Meriden, 1990s (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/New Year's Cards and thank-you notes, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1990 (Box 3)
  - Annual Campaign/Quarter Century Club, 1994 on (Box 3)
  - Annual campaign/Suburban, 1970s-1980s, 1970-1989 (Box 3)
- Series IV: Annual Campaign: Annual Campaign/Women's Division
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Business and Professional Women's Division, 1980s-present, 1980-2010 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Correspondence, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Jewish Awareness Day, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Five Year Strategic Plan, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Kickoff, Telethon, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Lion of Judah, undated (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Manuals for volunteers, 1977-1988 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Minutes, 1977-1988 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper clippings, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Newspaper Clippings, 2000- (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Programs, 1930 - 2000 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Programs, 2001- (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Special Projects/1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Division/Worker lists, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Philanthropy, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Annual Campaign/Women's Philanthropy, 2007 (Box 4)
- Series V: Annual Campaign: Annual Campaign/Leadership/Young Leadership
  - Annual Campaign/Leadership/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Young Adult Leadership, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 5)
  - Annual Campaign/Young Leadership/Miscellaneous, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 5)
  - Annual Campaign/Young Leadership/Miscellaneous, 2000-, 2000-2009 (Box 5)
  - Annual Campaign/Young Leadership/Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 5)
  - Annual Campaign/Young Leadership/Invitations and flyers, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 5)
  - Annual Campaign/Young Leadership/Better Living Though Community, booklet issued by UJA profiles Hartford's Seeds of Caring project on page 16, undated (Box 5)
- Series VI: Annual Campaign: Press releases, correspondence, SuperSunday
  - Annual Campaign/Correspondence, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Annual Campaign/Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 6)
  - Annual Campaign/Press releases, March – August, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Annual Campaign/Press releases, August – December 1991 (Box 6)
  - Annual Campaign/Super Sunday, 1980s-present, 1980-2012 (Box 6)
  - Annual Campaign/Super Sunday, newspaper clippings, undated (Box 6)
- Series VIIa: Annual Campaign: Oversize
  - Annual Campaign/Donors/Printout listing all donors, 1980s, 1980-1989
- Series VII: Board of Directors, Annual Meeting
  - Board of Directors/Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1954-1955 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1977-1978 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1987-1988, 1987-1998 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/2001 (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Meeting/2003 (Box 7)
  - Annual Meeting/2005 (Box 7)
  - Annual Meeting/2006 (Box 7)
  - Annual Meeting/2007 (Box 7)
  - Annual Meeting/2008 (Box 7)
  - Annual Meeting/2009 (Box 7)
  - Annual Meeting/2012 (Box 7)
    Annual Reports; Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford
- Series VIII: Board of Directors: Annual Reports, 1943-1961
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1943 (Hartford Jewish Welfare Fund) (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1944 (Hartford Jewish Welfare Fund) (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1947 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1948-1949 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1949-1950 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1955-56 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1956-1957 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1958-1959 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1961 (Box 8)
- Series IX: Board of Directors: Annual Reports, 1962-present
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report. 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 2002/no report published (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 2003/no report published (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 2004/no report published (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 2005 (Box 9)
  - Board of Directors/Annual Report, 2006 (Box 9)
- Series X: Board of Directors: By-laws, Minutes, Lists of Officers and Members, Presidents
  - Board of Directors/By-laws, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/By-laws, c. 1948 and 1970s, 1948-1979 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Community relations committee, public relations committee, undated (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Lists of committee members, 1948-1949 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Manual, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Members, 1949-1958 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Members, 2000s (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minute Books containing minutes of committees, minutes of annual meetings, lists of board members, 1940s, undated (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1951-1953 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1953-1956 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1956-1958 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 2001-2002 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/miscellaneous board officers and committees, 1944-1990 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Miscellaneous board officers and committees, 1991-present, 1991-2012 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Past presidents and chairmen of campaigns, list dated 1944-2007 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Catler, Marvin, 1993-1995, 1993-1996 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Feinstein, Arthur W. 1976-1978 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Feltman, Philip, 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Fierberg, I. Martin, 1974-1976 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Green, Louis, 1995-1997 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Konover, Simon, undated (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Naboicheck, Robert, 2001- (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Neiditz, Daniel, 1980-1982 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Rubenstein, Richard, 2003- (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Siskin, Robert, 1989-1991 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Stavis, Frank, 1991-1993 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Stern, Francis, 1952-1953 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Suisman, Michael, 1970-1974 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Suisman, Richard, 1987-1989 (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors/Presidents/Suissman, Ed, 1944-1946, 1944-1947 (Box 10)
- Series XI: Board of Directors: Executive Committee
  - Board of Directors/Executive committee/ Members 1950-1958 (Box 11)
  - Board of Directors/Executive committee/ Members 1990s- (Box 11)
  - Board of Directors/Executive committee/ Minutes, 1949-1950 (Box 11)
  - Board of Directors/Executive committee/ Minutes, 1950-1958, 1950-1957 (Box 11)
  - Board of Directors/Executive committee/ Minutes 1964-1965 (Box 11)
- Series XII: Administration
  - Administration/Administrative Structure, 1990s (Box 12)
  - Administration/Archives, 2002, information regarding the transfer of materials from the Federation to the JHSGH (Box 12)
  - Administration/Awards, 1950s-1970s, 1950-1979 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Awards, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Buildings/Zachs Campus and Weinberg, Hoffman and Mandel Buildings, 2000s see also Jewish Community Center (Box 12)
  - Administration/Buildings/Community Services building/BKM/floor plans, 2006 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Endowment Fund, 1970s-1990s, 1970-1999 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, undated (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, undated (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, 1980-1984 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, 1985-1999 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, 1990-1994 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, 1995-1999 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Financial Statements, 2000- (Box 12)
  - Administration/Grants, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 12)
  - Administration/Logo and name change, undated (Box 12)
  - Administration/Publicity, undated (Box 12)
- Series XIIa: Administration
  - Administration/FedBiz, undated (Box 12a)
  - Administration/Publicity, undated (Box 12a)
- Series XIII: Administration/Staff
  - Administration/Staff/Allen, Daniel, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Benefits, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Brody, Riki, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Chazan, Cindy, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Cooper, Don, undated (Box 13)
  - Adminstration/Staff/Dobin, Harriet, marketing consultant, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Gottlieb, Barnard, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Lind, Brenda, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/McAllister, Karen, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Miscellaneous, 1980s-2000s, 1980-2000 (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Newman, Leigh, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Schwartz, Catherine Fischer, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Shaliach, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Staff/Silverman, Judy, undated (Box 13)
  - Administration/Volunteers, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1989 (Box 13)
- Series XIV: Community Calendar and Commission on Jewish Education (CJE)
  - Community Calendar/1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1986-1987 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1987-1988 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1988-1989 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1989-1990 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1990-1991 (Box 14)
  - Community Calendar/1996-1997 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Adult Learning and Continuing Education Network, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Adult Studies/Miscellaneous, 1970s-1990s, 1970-1999 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Adult Studies/Miscellaneous, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Annual Conference, undated (Box 14)
  - CJE/Annual Reports, undated (Box 14)
  - CJE/Bible conference, undated (Box 14)
  - CJE/Beit Midrash, undated (Box 14)
  - CJE/Board members, undated (Box 14)
  - CJE/Committee on Communal Jewish Education/Minutes, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Committee on Jewish Education/Minutes, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Committee on Jewish Education/Minutes, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Committee on Jewish Education/visions of Jewish education from Hartford area community leaders, 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Continuity/Grants, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Continuity/Planning for Jewish Continuity, handbook published by the Jewish Education Service of North America and other organizations, 1996 (Box 14)
  - CJE/Continuity/Projects, Miscellaneous, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 14)
- Series XV: Commission on Jewish Education (CJE), C-H
  - CJE/Continuity/Report of the Jewish continuity Task Force, 1992 (Box 15)
  - CJE/Continuity/Report of the Jewish continuity Task Force/Responses, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 15)
  - CJE/Continuity/Report of the Jewish continuity Task Force/Responses, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 15)
  - CJE/Continuity/Report of the Jewish continuity Task Force/Responses/JHSGH, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 15)
  - CJE/Early Hartford Education, undated (Box 15)
  - CJE/Educators Council/ Connecticut Region Educators' Assembly, undated (Box 15)
  - CJE/Endowment Grants, undated (Box 15)
  - CJE/Funding, undated (Box 15)
  - CJE/General, 2 folders, undated (Box 15)
  - CJE/Hamerkaz, undated (Box 15)
  - CJE/Hamerkaz/Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 15)
  - CJE/Hartford Institute of Jewish Studies, an affiliate of the University of Hartford, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 15)
  - CJE/Hebrew College/Hartford Branch, 2 folders, undated (Box 15)
- Series XVI: Commission on Jewish Education (CJE), K-Z
  - CJE/Koopman Library, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/La'atid, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Lecture series, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/logo, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Long range planning, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 16)
  - CJE/Melitz Numbers 2000, 2000-2009 (Box 16)
  - CJE/Minutes, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Projects, Israel-related, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 16)
  - CJE/Reports, 2000- (Box 16)
  - CJE/Report of the CJE Task Force, 2006 (Box 16)
  - CJE/Special Education, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Staffing, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Suburban Services Task Force, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Synagogue Initiative Program, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 16)
  - CJE/Teacher training, undated (Box 16)
  - CJE/Transition to Jewish Federation Committee, 1996 (Box 16)
  - CJE/Weisel, Dr. A. Community Teach-in/Smorgasbord of Learning, undated (Box 16)
- Series XVII: Planning and allocation
  - Planning and Allocation/ Center for Judaic Studies/University of Connecticut, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/Allocation Proposals of beneficiary organizations, 1994-1997, 2994-1997 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/Allocation Proposals of beneficiary organizations, 1999 (Box 17)